[
  {
    "question_id": 550,
    "misconception_id": 1507,
    "misconception_name": "Carries out operations from left to right regardless of priority order",
    "misconception_type": "procedural",
    "construct_name": "Use the order of operations to carry out calculations involving addition, subtraction, multiplication, and/or division",
    "question_text": "Tom and Katie are discussing the order of operations\nTom says: \\( 3+2-1 \\equiv 3-1+2 \\)\nKatie says: \\( 3+2 \\times 1 \\equiv 2 \\times 1+3 \\)",
    "answer_a": "Only\nTom",
    "answer_b": "Only Katie",
    "answer_c": "Both Tom and Katie",
    "answer_d": "Neither is correct",
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "target_distractor": "B",
    "human_responses": 64,
    "human_distribution": {
      "B": 0.5625,
      "A": 0.2812,
      "C": 0.0938,
      "D": 0.0625
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.0938,
    "human_target_rate": 0.5625
  },
  {
    "question_id": 233,
    "misconception_id": 1507,
    "misconception_name": "Carries out operations from left to right regardless of priority order",
    "misconception_type": "procedural",
    "construct_name": "Write algebraic expressions with correct algebraic convention",
    "question_text": "Which answer shows the following calculation using the correct algebraic convention?\n\\(\n2 \\div(3+a \\times b)\n\\)",
    "answer_a": "\\( \\frac{2}{3}+a b \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( \\frac{2}{b(a+3)} \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( \\frac{2}{a b+3} \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( \\frac{2}{a \\times b+3} \\)",
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "target_distractor": "A",
    "human_responses": 173,
    "human_distribution": {
      "A": 0.7688,
      "C": 0.0983,
      "B": 0.0751,
      "D": 0.0578
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.0983,
    "human_target_rate": 0.7688
  },
  {
    "question_id": 1310,
    "misconception_id": 1507,
    "misconception_name": "Carries out operations from left to right regardless of priority order",
    "misconception_type": "procedural",
    "construct_name": "Answer decimal problems that require the use of BIDMAS",
    "question_text": "Which calculation should you do first?\n\\(\n((0.5 \\div(0.2+0.4)-0.3) \\times 0.6)\n\\)",
    "answer_a": "\\( 0.5 \\div 0.2 \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( 0.2+0.4 \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( 0.4-0.3 \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( 0.3 \\times 0.6 \\)",
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "target_distractor": "A",
    "human_responses": 693,
    "human_distribution": {
      "D": 0.482,
      "A": 0.2237,
      "B": 0.1501,
      "C": 0.1443
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.1501,
    "human_target_rate": 0.2237
  },
  {
    "question_id": 722,
    "misconception_id": 1214,
    "misconception_name": "When solving an equation, uses the same operation rather than the inverse",
    "misconception_type": "procedural",
    "construct_name": "Solve three or more step linear equations, with the variable on one side, involving negative integers",
    "question_text": "Tom and Katie are discussing how to solve:\n\\(\\frac{5 x}{3}-1=-2\\)\n\nTom says a correct next line of working could be: \\( 5 x-3=-6 \\)\n\nKatie says a correct next line of working could be: \\( \\frac{5 x}{3}=-3 \\)\n\nWho is correct?",
    "answer_a": "Only Tom",
    "answer_b": "Only Katie",
    "answer_c": "Both Tom and Katie",
    "answer_d": "Neither is correct",
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "target_distractor": "C",
    "human_responses": 47,
    "human_distribution": {
      "C": 0.5957,
      "D": 0.2128,
      "B": 0.1915
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0,
    "human_target_rate": 0.5957
  },
  {
    "question_id": 689,
    "misconception_id": 1214,
    "misconception_name": "When solving an equation, uses the same operation rather than the inverse",
    "misconception_type": "procedural",
    "construct_name": "Solve two-step linear equations, with the variable on one side, involving positive fractions",
    "question_text": "Solve the equation:\n\\(\n10=\\frac{5}{p}\n\\)",
    "answer_a": "\\( p=0.5 \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( p=50 \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( p=2 \\)",
    "answer_d": "There are no solutions",
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "target_distractor": "B",
    "human_responses": 1503,
    "human_distribution": {
      "D": 0.5908,
      "A": 0.1743,
      "B": 0.1497,
      "C": 0.0852
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.1743,
    "human_target_rate": 0.1497
  },
  {
    "question_id": 362,
    "misconception_id": 1214,
    "misconception_name": "When solving an equation, uses the same operation rather than the inverse",
    "misconception_type": "procedural",
    "construct_name": "Find the gradient of a line written in the form ax + by = c",
    "question_text": "A line has equation \\( 4 x+3 y=5 \\)\nWhat is it's gradient?",
    "answer_a": "\\( -4 \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( 4 \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( -\\frac{4}{3} \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( \\frac{4}{3} \\)",
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "target_distractor": "D",
    "human_responses": 461,
    "human_distribution": {
      "B": 0.6985,
      "D": 0.1193,
      "C": 0.1171,
      "A": 0.0651
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.1171,
    "human_target_rate": 0.1193
  },
  {
    "question_id": 1718,
    "misconception_id": 1597,
    "misconception_name": "Believes multiplying two negatives gives a negative answer",
    "misconception_type": "conceptual",
    "construct_name": "Expand two brackets with linear terms in the form (x + a)\u00b2",
    "question_text": "Which of the following answers shows a correct expansion and simplification of the expression below?\n\n\\(\n(x-3)^{2}\n\\)",
    "answer_a": "\\( x^{2}-6 x-9 \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( x^{2}-9 \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( x^{2}+9 \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( x^{2}-6 x+9 \\)",
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "target_distractor": "A",
    "human_responses": 207,
    "human_distribution": {
      "B": 0.5411,
      "A": 0.2512,
      "C": 0.1063,
      "D": 0.1014
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.1014,
    "human_target_rate": 0.2512
  },
  {
    "question_id": 139,
    "misconception_id": 1597,
    "misconception_name": "Believes multiplying two negatives gives a negative answer",
    "misconception_type": "conceptual",
    "construct_name": "Expand two brackets with linear terms in the form (ax + b)(cx + d)",
    "question_text": "Alison is expanding these two brackets.\nWhat should she get when she multiplies the two terms indicated by the arrows? ![The two brackets are (5p-4)(2p-3). The arrows are pointing at the -4 in the first bracket and the -3 in the second bracket.]()",
    "answer_a": "\\( +7 \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( -12 \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( +12 \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( -7 \\)",
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "target_distractor": "B",
    "human_responses": 122,
    "human_distribution": {
      "C": 0.6311,
      "B": 0.2131,
      "D": 0.0902,
      "A": 0.0656
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.6311,
    "human_target_rate": 0.2131
  },
  {
    "question_id": 1491,
    "misconception_id": 1597,
    "misconception_name": "Believes multiplying two negatives gives a negative answer",
    "misconception_type": "conceptual",
    "construct_name": "Raise negative numbers to powers",
    "question_text": "\\( (-2)^{4}= \\)",
    "answer_a": "\\( -16 \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( -8 \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( 16 \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( 8 \\)",
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "target_distractor": "A",
    "human_responses": 655,
    "human_distribution": {
      "A": 0.7435,
      "C": 0.0962,
      "B": 0.0931,
      "D": 0.0672
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.0962,
    "human_target_rate": 0.7435
  },
  {
    "question_id": 1390,
    "misconception_id": 217,
    "misconception_name": "When adding fractions, adds the numerators and denominators",
    "misconception_type": "conceptual",
    "construct_name": "Answer fraction problems that require the use of BIDMAS",
    "question_text": "\\( \\frac{1}{3}+\\frac{1}{2} \\times \\frac{1}{3}= \\)",
    "answer_a": "\\( \\frac{1}{2} \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( \\frac{5}{18} \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( \\frac{2}{9} \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( \\frac{1}{15} \\)",
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "target_distractor": "C",
    "human_responses": 103,
    "human_distribution": {
      "A": 0.4757,
      "C": 0.2816,
      "D": 0.1262,
      "B": 0.1165
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.4757,
    "human_target_rate": 0.2816
  },
  {
    "question_id": 1055,
    "misconception_id": 217,
    "misconception_name": "When adding fractions, adds the numerators and denominators",
    "misconception_type": "conceptual",
    "construct_name": "Add proper fractions with different denominators which do not share a common factor",
    "question_text": "The fractions in the two circles below add to give the fraction in the circle above.\n\nWhat should replace the question mark? ![Fractions 3/5 and 1/4 in two separate circles, both linked to a third circle above.]()",
    "answer_a": "\\( \\frac{4}{9} \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( \\frac{4}{20} \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( \\frac{7}{20} \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( \\frac{17}{20} \\)",
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "target_distractor": "A",
    "human_responses": 933,
    "human_distribution": {
      "B": 0.5959,
      "A": 0.164,
      "C": 0.1533,
      "D": 0.0868
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.0868,
    "human_target_rate": 0.164
  },
  {
    "question_id": 86,
    "misconception_id": 217,
    "misconception_name": "When adding fractions, adds the numerators and denominators",
    "misconception_type": "conceptual",
    "construct_name": "Add proper fractions with the same denominator",
    "question_text": "Work out:\n\\(\n\\frac{4}{11}+\\frac{7}{11}\n\\)\nWrite your answer in its simplest form.",
    "answer_a": "\\( \\frac{11}{22} \\)",
    "answer_b": "\\( \\frac{1}{2} \\)",
    "answer_c": "\\( \\frac{11}{11} \\)",
    "answer_d": "\\( 1 \\)",
    "correct_answer": "D",
    "target_distractor": "A",
    "human_responses": 49,
    "human_distribution": {
      "A": 0.5102,
      "D": 0.3061,
      "C": 0.102,
      "B": 0.0816
    },
    "human_correct_rate": 0.3061,
    "human_target_rate": 0.5102
  }
]